JESSE SWEDLUND | SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Summary

I am a former outdoor educator and documentary filmmaker with a passion for finding my flow state, being creative, and solving problems. My past work has provided me with a human-centered and compassionate approach to designing solutions, communicating a vision, and learning new skills.

Featured Projects

Haircutz | Full Stack Developer | Team Capstone Project https://dashboard.heroku.com/apps/haircutz

A two-player tower-defense web game using Phaser.js, Socket.IO, Node.js, Express, and Webpack.

- Designed a semi-authoritative server to create a synchronous game experience across two clients
- Wrote much of the game logic for interactive game objects
- Refactored file system with webpack and modularization
- Implemented an automated opponent for one player gameplay and deployed with Heroku.

Outdoor Equipment Inc | Developer | Team Project https://outdoor-equipment-incorporated.herokuapp.com/

An Ecommerce web application for buying outdoor goods built with React, Redux, Express, Sequelize, PostgreSQL, Sessions, Passport, Socket.IO, Stripe, Toast, and Nodemailer

- Designed the header and search bar functionality
- Implementing a guest checkout system using local storage
- Creating controlled React forms to add and edit products
- Wrote Redux thunks and reducers to make API calls and update state for products

River Coach | Sole Developer | 3-day Hack-a-thon Project A river paddling social media progressive web application built with React, Redux, Material UI, Node.js, and Express

- Implemented a service worker to cache important static assets for return visits to increase efficiency
- Created a manifest and in-app prompt to install app
- Built with functional React components using hooks and Redux thunk calls to a RESTful API that interacts with a PostgreSQL database using Sequelize.

Sudoku Solver | Sole Developer | Personal Project A web app that solves a sudoku using vanilla Javascript

- Created algorithms to emulate several sudoku strategies
- Designed interactive UI for entering sudoku puzzle

Publications

The Startup: "Progressive Web Applications: What They Are, Why They're Hot Right Now, and How to Build One"

Contact

P: 608-314-4093 | E: swedlundjesse@gmail.com

L: linkedin.com/in/jesseswedlund

G: github.com/jesseswedlund

Technical Skills

Proficient:

JavaScript; Node.js; React; Redux; Express; Sequelize; RESTFul APIs; PostgreSQL; Phaser.js; Socket.IO; CSS; HTML5; Github;

Knowledgeable:

Heroku; Webpack; Express-Session; Postico; SQL;

Some Familiarity:

Material UI; Passport; OAuth; Travis CI; Toastify; Nodemailer; Mocha; Chai; Testem;

Education

Fullstack Academy, New York, NY Dec 2020 Full-time Web Development Immersive Program

Northwestern University, Evanston, IL Dec 2013
Bachelor of Science: Radio, Television, and Film;
Philosophy

Work Experience

Fullstack Academy | Teaching Fellow

New York, NY/Remote | Jan 2021 - April 2021

- Debug, mentor, and teach JavaScript to over 50 students and oversee student projects as technical advisor and project manager
- Perform weekly code reviews with students and lead weekly technical interview white-boarding problems
- Interview prospective students for admissions

Outdoors For All Fdn. | Program Coordinator Seattle, WA | Jan 2019 - July 2020

 Managed skiing, climbing, kayaking, cycling, and camping programs for people with disabilities

Outward Bound Voyageur School | Lead Instructor *Ely, MN; Redford, TX* | *May 2014 - July 2017*

- Led up to 72-day wilderness expeditions, teaching lessons emphasizing leadership and communication
- Created spaces of compassion, empathy, and support

Crazy BenJee Productions | Co-founder/President Evanston, IL | Fall 2011-Winter 2016 http://www.tyslist-themovie.com/

 Co-Director/Producer of award winning feature length documentary film, "Ty's List"